Register of the Cuban Subject Collection, 1932-2004
Hoover Institution Archives
Cuban Subject Collection,
1932-2004
XX805
5 manuscript boxes, 5 phonorecords, 3 videotape cassettes, 4 phonotape cassettes (3.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Serial issues, pamphlets, leaflets, bulletins, speeches, newsletters, reports, and sound recordings, relating to political, social and economic conditions in Cuba, Cuban foreign relations, and the status of civil liberties in Cuba, primarily in the period since the revolution of 1959.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Cuba--Politics and government.; Cuba--Economic conditions.; Cuba--Social conditions.; Cuba--Foreign relations.; Civil rights--Cuba.; Cuba.; Phonorecords.; Video tapes.; Phonotapes.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1936-1994. (Boxes 1-2)
  Pamphlets, speeches, newletters, indexes, serial issues, statistics, memorandum, report, press release, atlas, brochure, article and clipping, primarily concerning political and economic conditions, foreign policy issues and human rights
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1971-1994. (Record cabinet, Tape cabinet)
  Phonorecords of songs and speeches, and two videotapes concerning political figures and human rights
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been received since December 1994
- SUBJECT FILE, 1936-1994
  - General. Pamphlets concerning Jose Marti and Maximo Gomez, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1933-1959. Indexes, newsletters and newspaper, 1936-1976. Includes official announcements from government of Fulgencio Batista (Folder 2)
  - 1959-
    - General. Atlas, pamphlets and booklet, primarily concerning political, judicial and foreign policy issues. Includes material on Cuban literature (Folder 3-4)
    - Castro, Fidel. Paper and speeches, 1962-1989. Includes analysis by Maurice Halperin (Folder 5)
    - Economy
      - Analyses. Pamphlets, 1970-1972, and transcript of speech by Paul Baran, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Statistics. Economic data published by government, 1985 (Folder 2)
    - Exile groups. Pamphlets and newsletter, 1960-1961. Includes material from Defensa Institucional Cubana and the Frente Revolucionario Democratico (Folder 3)
    - Granada. Pamphlet containing Cuban declarations about government of Maurice Bishop, 1983 (Folder 4)
    - Guevara, Ernesto "Che." Speech and serial issue containing biography, 1964-1994 (Folder 5)
    - Human rights. Memorandum, report, press release, statement, pamphlet and clipping, 1978-1994. Includes material from Amnesty International (Folder 6)
    - Partido Comunista de Cuba. Pamphlets and brochure, 1975-1987. Includes party platforms, resolutions and history (Folder 7)
    - United States. Pamphlet and article concerning Cuban-American relations, 1977-1984 (Folder 8)
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1971-1994
  - Phonorecords of songs and speeches
    - "Discurso Pronunciado por el Companero Lazaro Pena, Secretario General de la CTC en la Constitucion del SINTAE, 6/30/73." Speech, 1973 (Record-cabinet Record cabinet, Folder 1-2)
    - "Tail of a Tornado - Songs of the New Cuba," performed by Silvio Rodriguez, 1981 (Folder 3)
    - "Cuba Va! - Songs of the New Generation of Revolutionary Cuba," 1971 (Folder 4)
    - "Che Guevara Speaks - Habla Che Guevara," selected speeches, 1973 (Folder 5)
  - Videotapes concerning political figures and human rights issues
    - "Nobody Listened," directed by Nestor Almendros and Jorge Ulla, 1988 (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet, Folder 1)
    - "El Che Vive," documentary about Ernesto "Che" Guevara, 1994 (Folder 2)
- Incremental materials (Box 3-5)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.